### **Wakim Afara**

Highly organised and certified revenue manager with 14+ years hospitality experience. Skilled in identifying areas of business-development and optimising revenue-strategy through forecasting and data-based business analytics. Experienced in all aspects of the revenue, reservations and sales processes. Sense of responsibility and committed to proactively improve results through collaboration with all the stakeholders. Highly motivated to join your team in East Africa.

### **Competencies**

- P&L Statement Analysis
- Market & Competitor Analysis
- Regression Analysis (basic skills)
- Revenue Management:
  - Budgeting
  - Forecasting by Segment (+-5%)
  - · Pricing and Yield
  - Room Inventory Management
  - Benchmarking
  - Distribution
  - Promotions: Brand-page / OTAs
  - Rate Setup / Mapping
  - Displacement Analysis
  - Contract Negotiation
  - Relationship Management
  - Reservations
  - In-House Sales

### **Systems**

- Marriott Systems:
  - One Yield V2: Revenue System
  - R.I.S.E: Revenue Certificate
  - Marsha (working knowledge)
  - HPP
  - MRDW
  - MarRFP
- IDeaS: Revenue System
- Duetto: Revenue System
- Opera PMS
- HotSoft PMS
- Rate Code Setup & Loading
- RateTiger: Channel Manager
- YieldPlanet: Channel Manager
- OTA Promotions/Distribution
- Benchmarking Alliance
- STR
- OTA Insight
- Microsoft Excel (advanced)

#### **Personal Skills**

- Proactive
- Diplomatic
- Analytical
- Good Sense of Humour
- Languages:
  - English (fluent)
  - Swedish (fluent)
  - Arabic (fluent)

## **Experience**

- Cluster Revenue Manager: Ligula Hospitality Group (Jan 2020 Dec 2020)
- Managed 5 branded hotels (Total 768 Rooms) in Copenhagen, including: Airport Hotel, 290 Rooms.
- Re-established the revenue management process and strategy after 7 month gap of a revenue manager; Systems, process and communication across the hotels.
- Supported the area sales manager in developing a sales strategy.
- Project: Strategically positioned each hotel by changes to room-categories and pricing-strategy.
- Reviewed market segment-performance and identified areas of improvements.
- Adapting selling strategies and promotions during Covid-19 pandemic.
- Set-up and mapping of new distribution channel for all hotels.

#### • Cluster Revenue Manager: Core Hospitality (Sep 2018 - Aug 2019)

- Managed 3 branded hotels (Total 592 Rooms) in Copenhagen. Including: Airport hotel, 240 Rooms.
- Newly established management company in 2018.
- Pre-Opening/opening revenue manager: Moxy Copenhagen.
- Successful in price-positioning of Moxy Copenhagen in a highly competitive market.
- Successful in the pre-opening project and setup: rooms-budget, systems and routines.
- Established revenue management routines and areas of business improvements for Core Hospitality.
- Supported the hotel team with sales enquiries and account pricing recommendations.
- Managed all business and leisure group enquiries.
- Led the weekly revenue meeting and actioned strategy changes.
- Forecasting weekly, monthly and 12 month rolling by market segment.
- Managed three different revenue systems across three hotels.

### • Hotel Operations Manager: Connect Hotels (Oct 2016 - Jul 2018)

- Airport Hotel (131 Rooms + 400 Airport Car-Park) Stockholm. Reporting to cluster General Manager.
- Improved yield-management, pricing and reservations standards.
- Discovered & Recovered OTA non-refundable missed payments, Improved reservations routines.
- Improved service quality and we received Tripadvisor Certificate of Excellence in 2017.
- Exceeded financial goals VS budget through operational efficiencies; setting standards and systems to improve Reception, Reservations, F&B and Housekeeping departments.

### • Revenue & Reservations Manager: Kempinski Seychelles (Oct 2014 - May 2015

- Resort (150 Rooms) Re-established the revenue management processes and strategy after 10
  month gap of a revenue manager; Systems, process and communication across the hotel.
- Improved pricing strategy according to market segment.
- Recovered outstanding travel-agency late-payments and improved reservations routines.
- Trained and provided reservation and sales team with pricing recommendations.
- Led the weekly revenue meeting and actioned strategy changes.
- Forecasting per market segment: weekly, monthly 3 + 6 and +12 month.

#### • Revenue Manager: Scandic Hotels (2009 - 2011)

- Business hotel (208 Rooms). Maternity cover role & Project role (Fixed term contracts).
- Project: Scandic's first revenue cluster. Managed 2 hotels (Total 412 Rooms).
- $\mbox{\sc Improved}$  yield and pricing strategy for transient, corporate and group segments.
- Improved communication between sales, group reservations and front office team.
- Annual Rooms budget setup: Monthly, weekly, daily.
- Forecasting: weekly, monthly 3 + 6 and +12 month.

# • Front Office & Reservations: Malmaison Hotels UK (2005 - 2008)

- Front office and Reservations: Supervisory and Management roles.

### **Education & Certificates**

### • Master's Degree: International Hotel Management (2012 - 2013)

- Oxford Brookes University: United Kingdom

#### Certificate: Certified Revenue Management Executive (CRME) (2020)

- HSMAI: Hospitality Sales & Marketing Association International: Online Certificate

- Certificate: Advanced Revenue Management: Pricing & Demand Strategies (2018)
- Cornell University: Online Certificate
- Certificate: Hotel Real Estate Investments and Asset Management (2017 2018)
- Cornell University: Online Certificate